Guide to the Ford Madox Ford collection, [ca. 1850]-1973
Ford, Ford Madox collection,
- Series II. Outgoing correspondence
  - A-B
    - Stella Bowen
      - TL[telegram] to Stella Bowen, Dec.18, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 29C, Folder 32)
        New York; Horriblement deccu nai pas pu embarquer suis tout seul[Julian Loewe papers]
      - ALS to Stella Bowen, Dec.21, 1927; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 29C, Folder 33)
        New York; Darling: I expect this will be the last letter [Julian Loewe papers] [Copy in Box 29, folder 113]
      - TL[telegram] to Stella Bowen, Dec.28, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 29C, Folder 34)
        New York; Cabled twenty-fourth all well [Julian Loewe papers]
      - TL[telegram] to Stella Bowen, Dec.30, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 29C, Folder 35)
        New York; So sorry yours delayed yes take apartment love [Julian Loewe papers]
      - TL[telegram] to Stella Bowen, Dec.31, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 29C, Folder 35.5)
        New York; Happy Happy New Year to you all Ford [Julian Loewe papers]
      - TLS to Stella Bowen, Jan.6, [1928]; 2 leaves + envelope (Box 29C, Folder 36)
        New York; Darling:, I have yours of the 27th Dec. [ Mistakenly dated 1927] [Julian Loewe papers]
      - TLS to Stella Bowen, Jan.13, [1928]; 1 leaf (Box 29C, Folder 37)
        New York; Darling, Thank you for your letter of the 3rd [Julian Loewe papers]
      - TLS to Stella Bowen, Jan.20, [1928]; 1 leaf (Box 29C, Folder 38)
        New York; Darling, I hope this will be the last letter I shall write you from here [Misdated 1927][Julian Loewe papers]
      - TLS to Stella Bowen, [Apr.18, 1928]; 1 leaf (Box 29C, Folder 39)
        [Paris] My dear, I thought you would like to know that E.J. was well and duly pickled [Julian Loewe papers]
      - ALS to Stella Bowen, May 20, 1933; 1 leaf + l (Box 29C, Folder 40)
        Toulon; Dear Stella: I enclose a letter authorizing you to deal with [Enclosed TLS to Bowen, dated May 20, 1933 delegated her as his agent for "Towards to Tomorrow"][Julian Loewe papers]
      - TLS to Stella Bowen, Oct.8, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 29C, Folder 41)
        Toulon; Dear Stella, I don't know whether Faber's wanting a[Julian Loewe papers]
      - TL[telegram] to Stella Bowen, Sept.23, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 29C, Folder 42)
        New York; IN CASE WAR WOULD YOU WISH SEND JULIE [Julian Loewe papers]
      - TL to Stella Bowen, [1917-1919]; 65 letters (Box 29D, Folder 1)
        Transcripts of Ford-Bowen correspondence in the "Redcar" period
      - TL to Stella Bowen, [1919-1920; 33 letters (Box 29D, Folder 2)
      - TL to Stella Bowen, 1923; 3 letters (Box 2E, Folder 1)
        Transcripts copies of Ford-Bowen correspondence from Saint-Jean-Cap-Ferrat, Italy, with the Pounds.
      - TL to Stella Bowen, [1926]; 1 letter (Box 29E, Folder 2)
        Transcripts copies of Ford-Bowen correspondence from Arles.
      - TL to Stella Bowen, 1926-1927; 14 letters (Box 29E, Folder 3)
        Transcripts copies copies of Ford-Bowen correspondence from New York to Paris.
      - TL to Stella Bowen, 1927; 3 letters (Box 29E, Folder 4)
        Transcripts copies of Ford-Bowen correspondence during Ford's trip to the Midwest U.S.A.
      - TL to Stella Bowen, 1927-1928; 41 letters (Box 29E, Folder 5)
        Transcripts copies of Ford-Bowen correspondence from Ford's second NY trip.
    - TL[copy] to Jenny Bradley, Dec.13, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Paris; Yours of the 6th inst. I had not realized that Bradley had been so ill.
    - TL[copy] to Jenny Bradley, Dec.18, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 2)
      Paris; dear Jenny, I gathered from your letter that you knew I should not want to be published by a Nazi publisher
    - TL[copy] to Jenny Bradley, Jan.30, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 3)
      [Paris] Dear Jennie, As Miss Scriabine is still signing your letters I take it that Bradley is not back
    - TL[copy] to Jenny Bradley, Mar.9, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 4)
      [London] Dear Jenny, Thank you for the cheque for frs.1000 which duly reached me
    - TL[copy] to Jenny Bradley, Mar.19, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 5)
      London; Dear Jenny, If you have not already paid in the Lippincott advance will you kindly pay frs.200
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Jan.7, 1926; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 6)
      Toulon; Dear Bradley, Here is another collection what we used to call bumph from Pinker and Dent.
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Aug.3, 1926; 2 leaves (Box 30, Folder 7)
      Toulon; Dear Bradley, This here correspondence business is becoming portentous!
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Nov.28, 1927; 2 leaves (Box 30, Folder 8)
      [New York; My Dear Bradley, I have been very lazy about writing to you
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, [1928?]; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 9)
      [New York] Dear Bradley, I have not got time to go into the whole of your letter
    - TL to William A. Bradley, May 11, 1928; 3 leaves + 3 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      Paris; My dear Bradley, Ref. our conversation of this evening. [With carbon of letter]
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Jul.13, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 11)
      New York; Dear Bradley, I forwarded you yesterday per the Majestic the remainder of the ms. of "A Little Less Than Gods"
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Jul.25, 1928; 3 leaves (Box 30, Folder 12)
      New York; Dear Bradley, I expect to sail on Friday, day after tomorrow, by S.S. Patria of the Fabre line
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Aug.27, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 13)
      Carqueiranne; Dear Bradley, Under separate envelopes one addressed to Brandt c/o you, I am sending you two copies
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Apr.4, 1919; 5 leaves + 2 (Box 30, Folder 14)
      New York; Dear Bradley, Below is a list of payments made to me by Brandt & Brandt since the 1st of January [With second copy of letter]
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, May 16, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 15)
      [New York] Dear Bradley, NOTTERDAM After working practically night and day for some time past
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Sept.17, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 16)
      [Toulon?] Dear Bradley, I should be obliged if you would let me have your copy of my agreement
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Sept.23, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 17)
      Toulon; Dear Bradley, My New York agent, Miss Ruth Kerr... has cabled to ask me if I can arrange
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Mar.12, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 18)
      Paris; dear Bradley, Thank you. I think you might as well send that frs.500 to my account on Monday.
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Apr.19, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 19)
      [Toulon] Dear Bradley, I enclose a letter I just had from Liferight and would be glad of your reqaction to it
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Apr.20, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 20)
      Dear Bradley, Yours of the nineteenth of April. The length of "The Rash Act" as far as I can tell
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Apr.21, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 21)
      [Paris] Dear Bradley, Enclosed pleas find the synopsis of "The Rash Act".
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Apr.23, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 22)
      Toulon; Dear Bradley, Here is my agreement with Liveright.
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, May 23, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 23)
      [Toulon] Dear Bradley, I enclose for your information Liveright's reply to mine.
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Jun.2, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 24)
      Toulon; Dear Bradley, Thank you. I am writing to Pillement by this post.
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Jun.8, 1932; 3 leaves (Box 30, Folder 25)
      [Toulon] Dear Bradley, I wish we could bet you to look at things in a more realistic manner
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Jul.19, 1932; 2 leaves (Box 30, Folder 26)
      Toulon; Dear Bradley, Thanks for yours of the seventeenth.
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, [Aug..]1, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 27)
      Toulon; Dear Bradley, I have received from Miss Kerr an offer for "Ladies Whose Bright Eyes"
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Aug.11, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 28)
      [Toulon] Dear Bradley, I have mailed today the article to Harper's, it being as you'll observe
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Jan.22, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 29)
      [Paris?] Dear Bradley, Will you please as I asked you in the beginning, appoint someone in New York
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Mar.7, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 30)
      [Paris] Dear Bradley, Here is the Cape agreement, signed, with an alteration
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Mar.8, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 31)
      Paris; Dear Bradley, Ref. Lippincott's payment: please do not have my share of this converted [Draft[copy] of this letter on verso]
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Mar.15, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 32)
      Paris; Dear Bradley, Herewith the article which I have cut out of the first chapter of "Towards Tomorrow"
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Mar.31, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 33)
      [Paris] Dear Bradley, I think the ENGLISH REVIEW rate of pay is very lov and I would rather not be printed by them.
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, May 8, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 34)
      [Toulon] Dear Bradley, What is the position with regard to the collected Tietjens books
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, May 14, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 35)
      [Toulon? Paris?] Dear Bradley, Thank you. I would be very glad if you would let me have
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, May 22, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 36)
      [Toulon] Dear Bradley, Here are the latest of Boni's accounts I could find you.
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Jun.18, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 37)
      [Toulon] Dear Bradley, Thank you for your letter. I forwarded the mss of TOWARDS TOMORROW
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Sept.10, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 38)
      [Toulon?] Dear Bradley, Your letter of the 2nd inst. seems little less than libellous
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Oct.31, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 39)
      [Paris? Toulon?] Dear Bradley, I trust you are now sufficiently restored to attend to business
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Nov.2, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 40)
      Toulon; Dear Bradley, I have forwarded signed to Stella a document of which below please find a copy
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Nov.5, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 41)
      [Paris? Toulon?] Dear Bradley, I must confess to being disappointed at the rate obtained from Lippincott's
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Jan.18, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 42)
      Paris; Dear Bradley, I forward herewith for your information copy of a letter that I wrote to Lippincott's
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Feb.25, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 43)
      [Toulon?] Dear Bradley, Have you another copy of my HISTORY OF OUR OWN TIME?
    - TL[copy] to William A. Bradley, Sept.13, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 44)
      [Toulon] Dear Bradley, I sent the complete typescript of the book on Provence to Lippincotts
    - TL[copy to Carl Brandt, [1928?]; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 45)
      [New York] Dear Brandt, The time appears to have come, much as I dislike it,
    - TL[copy to Carl Brandt, Mar.5, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 46)
      [Paris?] My Dear Carl, I wish I could have caught you in London for I am just in the process of changing
    - TL[copy to Carl Brandt, Jul.16, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 47)
      New York; My dear Brandt, Ref. my future plans etc. These naturally depend on my resources
    - TL[copy to Carl Brandt, Apr.21, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 48)
      New York; Dear Carl, With reference to our telephone conversation of yesterday I enclose
    - TL[copy to Carl Brandt, Apr.28, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 49)
      [Paris?] Dear Brandt, I enclose herewith a letter from Brentano's about that French prize business.
    - TL[copy to Carl Brandt, May 31, [1929]; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 50)
      [New York] Dear Brandt, "History of Our Own Time". If Miss. Baumgarten is to handle the above [Misdated 1921]
    - TL[copy] to Brandt & Brant, Jul.2, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 51)
      New York; Dear Sirs, Your MS/WK of the 30th ult. I have to thank you for the above which seems to me to be correct
    - TL[copy] to Brandt & Brant, Sept.21, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 52)
      [Paris?] Dear Sirs, I have your accounts brom Boni & Boni shewing balance of $82.84 in my favour.
    - TL[copy] to Brandt & Brant, Oct.11, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 53)
      [Paris?] Dear Sirs, I should be much obliged by an answer to mine of the 20th ult.
    - TL[draft] to Brandt & Brant, [193-?]; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 54)
      [Paris? Toulon?] Kindly remind Viking I re-wrote Poor Man at urgen request of Oppenheimer
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Feb.19, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 30, Folder 55)
      Paris; My Dear Brewer, Comparing the above date with that on your letter I observe that your letter has taken
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Oct.24, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 30, Folder 56)
      [New York] Dear Joseph, I don't know anything about that WWJ broadcast. No one has said anything
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Feb.17, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 30, Folder 57)
      [New York] Dear Brewer, I have taken the liberty of inserting your name among thos of the charter memembers
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Mar.24, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 58)
      [New York] My dear Joseph, My suggestion that I should pay a yearly visit to Olivet if I accept the
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Apr.22, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 59)
      [New York] Dear Mr. President, I think you and the college are really to be congratulated on the notable progress
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, May 8, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 60)
      [New York] My Dear Joseph: From enclosed which please return you will observe that I am still trying
    - TL[copy] to the Trustees, the British Museum, May 9, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 61)
      [London] My Lords and Gentlemen, I have the honour to apply to you in the following circumstances
    - TLS to Heywood Broun, Dec.17, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 62)
      New York; Dear Heywood Broun, I'd be glad of a word or two with you shomewhere, sometime [Broun's response on recto]
    - TL{copy] to Heywood Broun, May 12, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 63)
      New York; My Dear Heywood Broun, I have been and always am so insupportably busy mostly of other people's affairs
    - ALS to "Grandpapa", [Jul.?]5, 1883; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 64)
      [Folkestone] Dear Grandpapa, I am so glad you are well
    - TL[copy,fragment] to Gerald Bullett, [Aug.24, 1933]; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 65)
      [Toulon]...and used for manuals in University English Classes.
    - TL[copy,fragment] to Joseph Brewer, Aug.24, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 66)
      [Toulon] Dear Sir, Anything that calls for attention to writing in a world that avoids with disgust
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Sept.24, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 67)
      [Toulon] Dear Mr. Bullett, The QUICK AND THE DEAD is pretty good stuff and you ought to be pleased with it
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Oct.8, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 68)
      [Toulon?] Dear Mr. Bullet, I shall be delighted to write a notice of the Cantos for you
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Oct.29, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 69)
      [Toulon] Dear Mr. Bullett, I sent the review to Ezra off some days ago.
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Jan.14, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 70)
      Paris; My Dear Mr. Bullett, I am really grieved to see that the WEEKEND REVIEW is stopping
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Brewer, Sept.14, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 70.5)
      Villa Paul; My Dear Bullett; I am a swine not to have written to you before
    - TL[copy] to William C. Bullitt, Mar.10, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 71)
      [New York] My dear Bullitt: I am thinking of re-starting the TRANSATLANTIC REVIEW
    - TL[copy] to Basil Bunting, Sept.7, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 72)
      [Toulon] Dear Bunting: Yea, about five hundred works will do very well. Thank you.
    - TLS[copy] to Whit Burnett, Aug.12, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 73)
      Boulder; Dear Burnett, Miss Whipple tells me that you would like my opinion on her novel
    - TL[copy] to H.P. Burton, Feb.19, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 74)
      [New York] Dear Sir, I am sending you herewith my contribution to your symposium
    - TL[copy] to Fanny Butcher, Mar.19, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 75)
      Paris; Dear Miss Butcher, Alas, 'twas not to be. I only got your kind invitation this morning
    - TLS[copy] to George T. Bye, Dec.28, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 76)
      [New York] My dear Bye, I have told Vernon of the Dial Press that you will communicate with him
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Feb.25, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 77)
      [New York] Dear Bye, I think the time has come when, if you have not already done it,
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Mar.8, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 78)
      New York; My Dear Bye, Ref. Publisher. With regard to Doubledays on any other publisher I want
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Mar.15, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 79)
      [New York?] Dear Bye, Will you please deal with this? I don't know anything about these people
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Mar.22, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 80)
      [New York?] Dear Bye, Here is the article on species. It makes almost six thousand words
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Mar.25, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 81)
      Clarksville; Dear Bye, Herewith is the first of the articles and also Mr. Ford's illustrations
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Jun.10, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 82)
      Olivet; Dear Bye, I send you herewith an article on Denver, Colorado which you can offer to CAVALCADE
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Jun.11, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 83)
      Clarksville; Dear Bye, Thank you for the blessed word "intellectual" which Mor. Costain or Mr. Spock has invented
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Jun.25, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 84)
      Clarksville; Dear Bye, I am getting extremely anxious about the fate of those drawings of Boston
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Jun.29, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 85)
      [Olivet] Dear Bye, I suppose that's another $300 gone west - that is why
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Oct.31, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 86)
      Olivet; Dear Bye, According to our present schedule we shall leave New York by the Lafayette
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Nov.29, 1938; 3 leaves (Box 30, Folder 87)
      [New York] Dear Bye, The three books I discussed with Howe are as follows: 1-The quite provisional title
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, Apr.14, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder 88)
      [Olivet?] Dear Bye, Here we are in the midst of daily snow storms,
    - TL[copy] to George T. Bye, May 30, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 30, Folder 89)
      [New York?] Dear Bye, Will you please note the following details: Our address for the present
  - C-J
    - AL[draft] to Henry S. Canby, [193-?]; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 1)
      [New York] Dear Dr. Canby, I'm sorry but I think I'd better send the Gibbs book back to you [not in Ford's hand]
    - AL[draft] to Henry S. Canby, [Dec., 1934?]; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 2)
      [Paris] Dear Dr. Canby, I have at last got Gibbs' book. How much do you want me to write about it? [ Not in Ford's hand]
    - TL[copy] to Jonathan Cape Ltd., Aug.26, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 3)
      [Paris?] Dear Sirs, Yours of the 24th Inst. I note what you say ref. ENGLISH COUNTRY.
    - TL[copy] to Jonathan Cape Ltd., Feb.4, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 4)
      [Paris?] Dear Sirs, Notterdam. The present would seem to be a good time to publish.
    - TL[copy] to Jonathan Cape Ltd., Feb.10, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 5)
      [Paris] Dear Sirs, Notterdam. At your request I am having forwarded to you a copy
    - TL[copy] to Jonathan Cape Ltd., Feb.24, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 6)
      [Paris] Dear Sirs, WHEN THE WICKED MAN. Mr. Ford asks me to say that he does not see his way [Not in Ford's hand]
    - TL[copy] to Jonathan Cape Ltd., Mar.6, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 7)
      [Paris] Dear Sirs, WHEN THE WICKED MAN. I am forwarding you by this mail under another cover [Not in Ford's hand]
    - TL[copy] to Jonathan Cape, [1933?]; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 8)
      Paris; My Dear Cape, I do hope you are not going to use this lugubrious dirge
    - TL[copy] to Jonathan Cape, Mar.2, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Paris; My Dear Cape, I am having sent you under another cover a copy of an American novel
    - TL[copy] to Jonathan Cape, Mar.2, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 10)
      Paris; Dear Cape, Ref. the agreement Bradley has just sent me.
    - TL[copy] to Jonathan Cape, Mar.13, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 11)
      Paris; My dear Cape, Thank you; I am really much obliged. I enclose the blurb herewith.
    - TL[copy] to Robert I Center, Mar.15, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 12)
      Toulon; Dear Sir, I am much flattered by your letter of the 28th April.
    - TL[copy] to Robert I Center, May 25, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 13)
      Toulon; Dear Sir, I am sending you under separate cover, the ms. of THE HISTORY OF OUR OWN TIME
    - TL[copy] to Robert I Center, Jun.18, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 14)
      [Toulon] Dear Sir, I am much obliged to you for your letter of the 3rd inst.
    - TL[copy] to John Chamberlain, Nov.21, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 15)
      [Toulon?] Dear Sir, I think you should launch a thunderbolt
    - TL[copy] to Jacques Chambrun, Nov.19, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 16)
      [New York] Dear Mr. Chambrun, As I have said, I have no articles by me.
    - TL[copy] to Jacques Chambrun, Jan.28, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 17)
      [New York] Dear Sir, If you do not within twenty four hours return the ms. of my article on Weather
    - TL[copy] to Woodburn Chase, Mar.1, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 18)
      New York; Dear Mr. Chase: I am flattered that you should invite me to join your committee
    - TL[copy] to [?] Child, Aug.16, 1909; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 19)
      London; Dear Child. This is, just to tell you that it is certainly my intention
    - TL[copy] to Padraic Colum, Sept.26, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 20)
      [Paris?] Dear Colum, I really wish you would let me know what are your intentions
    - TL[copy to Saxe Commins, Mar.11, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 21)
      New York; Dear Mr. Commins, I regret to say that Mrs. Archibald MacColl, the lady whose novel
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Conrad, [Sept., 1916]; 2 leaves (Box 31, Folder 22)
      Attd. 9/Welch; My Dear Conrad, I have just had a curious opportunity with regard to sound
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Conrad, Sept.7, 1916; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 23)
      Attd.9/Welch; Dear Conrad, I wrote these rather hurried notes yesterday because we were being shelled
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Conrad, Oct.6, 1916; 2 leaves (Box 31, Folder 24)
      9/Welch; My Dear, I will continue for yr. information and necessary action,
    - TL[copy] to Joseph Conrad, Dec.19, 1916; 2 leaves (Box 31, Folder 25)
      Rouen; My dear, It must be all of five months since I heard from you
    - ALS to Joseph Conrad, [Apr., 1924?]; 1 leaf (Box 31, Folder 26)
      [Paris] Dear Conrad, Wd. you look at reverse and return it? [Verso is TLS Victor Llana to Ford, April 16, 1924]
    - TL[draft,fragment] to Joseph Conrad, 1 leaf; [1924?] (Box 31, Folder 27)
      Paris; Dear Conrad, I am sorry to trouble you again about the affairs of "Romance"
    - TL{copy,draft] to Messrs. Kovici [i.e.Convici], Jan.5, 1927; 2 leaves (Box 31, Folder 28)
      New Yokr; Dear Kovici [sic], I could not answer yours of the 31st ult. before